(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T01:40:54.065808",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
すてきなホリデイ
Wonderful Holiday
近づいている冬の足音
Winter's footsteps are drawing near
耳を澄ませば聞こえる鈴の音
If you listen closely, you can hear the ringing bells
寝ぼけた頭に響く目覚ましを
An alarm clock ringing in my sleepy head,
手さぐりで止めたあと雪の気配
after turning it off by feel, I sense the snow.
始まりを告げるすてきな季節が
A wonderful season announcing a new beginning...
Happy holidays, happy holidays
What a glorious time of year!
すやすやと眠る子供達の手に
In the hands of peacefully sleeping children,
抱かれたテディベアもしもう待ちきれない
even the hugged teddy bears can't wait any longer.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
as if to wipe away all the sad things that happened.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Come on, once you take off your pajamas, let's go out,
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
running past the roadside trees that are turning white.
華やぎ始めた街は急ぎ足
The city decorated in holiday cheer moves at a hurried pace,
贈り物決まる頃黄昏れてく
as twilight falls around the time gifts are chosen.
かじかんだ指をママが温めるね
Mom warms up your cold, numb fingers.
Happy holidays,happy holidays What a glorious time of year!
Happy holidays, happy holidays! What a glorious time of year!
大切なものはみんなそばにある
Everything that's precious is right by your side.
穏やかな毎日が続くぜいたく
The true luxury of peaceful days continuing...
クリスマスがもうじきやって来る
Christmas will be here very soon!
うれしさをかくせない犬や猫まで
Even the dogs and cats can't hide their joy,
もみの木に灯る明かりをうけて
basking in the glowing lights of the Christmas tree.
いつもよりやさしそうなパパの目が笑ってる
Dad's eyes are smiling, looking gentler than usual.
クリスマスは誰にもやって来る
Christmas comes for everyone.
もしもひとりぼっちでも淋しがらずに
Even if you're all alone, don't feel lonely.
心に住むサンタに呼びかけて
Call out to the Santa living in your heart.
幼い頃の夢を思い出してごらんよ
Try recalling the dreams you had when you were young.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
as if to wipe away all the sad memories.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Come on, change out of your pajamas and let's go out!
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
Dashing through the tree-lined streets gradually turning white.
Happy happy holidays
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気マジック
Ah, the town looking like whipped cake, Love! Snow! Truly Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti falling from the sky...
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ Woo
...are angel wings celebrating the winter festival, woo!
白銀の国へ出かけるの Go Go Go
Heading out to the silver snow land, Go Go Go!
雪の汽車が街を駆け Choo Choo Choo
The snow train dashes through town, Choo Choo Choo!
絵本みたいな景色を 君に見せてあげるから
I'll show you a scenery straight out of a picture book.
願い込めて呪文さあ (さあ) 唱えて (さんはい)
Put your wishes into a spell, come on (come on) chant it! (1, 2, 3)
ABCDFドシシララシシマジカルミラクルクル Pop!
ABCDF Do-Do-Ti-Ti-La-La-Ti-Ti Magical Miracle-cle Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気 Magic
Ah, the town like a whipped-cream cake, Love! Snow! Truly Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
The confetti falling from the sky are angel wings celebrating the winter festival!
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は 好き！雪！本気 Magic
The aurora-colored town lit up bright, Love! Snow! Truly Magic!
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If we could stay as kids forever, Dream Land!
Ladies and gentlemen, Welcome to Snow Miko!
ツンと冷たい季節が好き Love Love Love
I love the crisp, cold season! Love Love Love!
アイスも魔法もとけないように ヒューヒューヒュー
So that neither the ice nor the magic melts, whew-whew-whew!
ずっとこのままじゃダメなの？
Is it no good to stay like this forever?
やっぱりドキドキしたいな
After all, I want my heart to flutter!
未来 求め呪文 今 (なう) 唱えて (さんはい)
Seeking the future, chant the spell now (now)! (1, 2, 3)
1234 水金地火木マジカルミラクルクル Pop!
1234 Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Magical Miracle-cle Pop!
Ah ホップしたウサギのような気分 好き！雪！本気 Magic
Ah, feeling like a hopping rabbit, Love! Snow! Truly Magic!
大地がくれる元気 得たら 思い通り明日を生きていけるよ
Once you gain energy from the earth, you can live tomorrow just as you wish!
まぶしい白に染まるハート 君に 好き！雪！本気 Magic
To you, whose heart is dyed in dazzling white, Love! Snow! Truly Magic!
大人のふりなんていいじゃん
Who cares about acting like an adult?
I hear that beat from town
The cute angel will come down
This is my home I'll let you know
NAMARA fantastic!
The snowscape is lyrical
The street gonna be magical
The street's gonna be magical
今日の寒さも忘れるように（わすれちゃって）
So we can forget today's coldness too (just forget it)
悩みだって 悩みだって 凍らせて
Let all our worries freeze away
消せる魔力よ（もうかい）
With magic that can erase them (once more)
ABCD ドド シシ ララ シシ マジカル ミラクル クル Pop!
ABCD Do-Do Ti-Ti La-La Ti-Ti Magical Miracle Kuru Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, the town looking like whipped cream on a cake
好き！雪！本気 Magic
Like! Snow! Serious Magic
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti falling from the sky
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
Is angel wings celebrating the winter festa
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は
The lit-up aurora-colored town
好き！雪！本気 Magic
Like! Snow! Serious Magic
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If I could stay a child, it'd be Dream Land
いいじゃん！
Isn't that great!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to...
らしくいていいよね？
...be myself, is that okay?
さくらんぼメッセージ
[Cherry Message]
弱気で流したジングル
A jingle played out of nervousness
いつもドキドキだね第一声
My very first greeting is always nerve-wracking
にゃっはろ〜！
Nyahallo~!
震えた声も ノートの文字も
Even my trembling voice and handwriting in my notebook
みんなみんな手繋いで GO！
Let's all hold hands together and GO!
変わってるねって そーなんだ なんて言ったの？ まぁいっか
"You're weird" "Oh really?" "What did you say?" "Oh well"
飲み込んじゃってきた言葉も
Even the words I swallowed down
君と笑った声で ほら咲いて
Look, they bloom with the sound of our laughter
ばんざい！
Hurrah!
こんな私でも
Even for someone like me
モーマンタイ！
No problem!
好きだって ねぇほんと？
Saying you like me, hey, really?
冗談？ わかりそう？
A joke? Can you tell?
どっち？ わかんない！
Which is it? I don't know!
さくらんぼメッセージ 受け取って いっせーのーせで！
Receive this Cherry Message, on the count of three!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
Surely it will make your heart flutter even more
さくらんぼメッセージ つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
Packing the Cherry Message tightly into a bud!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to...
らしくいていいよね？
...be myself, is that okay?
なんて返そっか 没頭！
How should I reply? Completely absorbed!
頭が フットー！
My brain is boiling over!
素直が モットー！
Being honest is my motto!
ゲームの中なら Get you!
If it were inside a game, Get you!
攻略 しょっちゅう？
Beating the game all the time?
百発 百中！ なのにね
Bullseye 100% of the time! And yet...
どったんばったん 踊ったんなら 悩んじゃったって ブギウギ！
If we dance noisily around, even worrying turns into boogie-woogie!
ハード ずっきゅん ばっきゅん スタートボタン 押せるかな？
Heart going zukyun bakyun, can I press the start button?
ちゃんと言ったっけ？ どーだっけ？
Did I say it properly? How was it?
言わなきゃよかった？ そーだっけ
Should I not have said it? Was that so?
抑え込んじゃって また焼きもち
Holding it back and getting jealous again
あー私なんて しゃがみそうになって
"Ah, someone like me..." almost crouching down in frustration
これが私だもん 大賛成！
But this is who I am, total approval!
行くよって ほらこっち！ 右？曲がっちゃう？ 左？迷っちゃう！ まっすぐ！
Let's go, look over here! Right? Turn around? Left? Lost! Straight ahead!
さくらんぼメッセージ 春めいて 舞って 飛び立って！
Cherry Message, feeling like spring, dancing, taking flight!
そっと じっと しゅんとしちゃう日も
Even on days when you feel down quietly and silently
さくらんぼメッセージ 瞳に ぱっと 映るよ！
Cherry Message will instantly reflect in your eyes!
背中を押して メロディー
Giving a gentle push on your back, melody
好きでいて いいよね？
It's okay if I keep loving you, right?
誰かじゃなくて 君がいいよって
"Not anyone else, I want you," you said
絶対！ 何度でも言うよ もう一回！
Definitely! I'll say it as many times, one more time!
好きだって ねぇほんと！
Saying you like me, hey, really?
冗談？ わかりそう？ どっち？ わかんない！
A joke? Can you tell? Which is it? I don't know!
本当だー！
It's true!
さくらんぼメッセージ 受け取って いっせーのーせで！
Receive this Cherry Message, on the count of three!
きっと もっと キュンとしちゃうような
Surely it will make your heart flutter even more
さくらんぼメッセージ つぼみに ぎゅっと 詰め込んで！
Packing the Cherry Message tightly into a bud!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to...
らし くい て いいよね？
...be myself, is that okay?
好きでいて いいよね？
It's okay to keep loving you, right?
はいー！にゃっはろ〜！
Alright! Nyahallo~!
ピンクのアイドルクリスマス さくらみこ新衣装お披露目ライブに来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Pink Idol Christmas Sakura Miko New Outfit Reveal Live!
そしてみんな、メリークリスマス！イェーイ！
And everyone, Merry Christmas! Yay!
えー、本日クリスマスはなんと！みこちゃんのホロライブ加入記念日でもありまーす！
Um, today on Christmas is also, amazingly, Miko-chan's Hololive joining anniversary!
おめでとー！ありがとー！ありがとー！
Congratulations! Thank you! Thank you!
えー、そして！お披露目したこちらの衣装は、200万人記念で作らせていただいた新衣装のルームウェア... ルームウェア衣装となっておりまーす！
Um, and! This outfit I revealed was created to celebrate reaching 2 million subscribers—it's a new roomwear... roomwear outfit!
可愛いでしょう？
Cute, right?
あのね
You know...
ま、いつも新衣装で悩んでるんですけど
Well, I always struggle with new outfits,
作りたいなってずっと思ってたんだけど、なかなかね
but I've always wanted to make this, though it was hard to...
踏み切れなかったこのルームウェアをね
take the plunge on this roomwear outfit,
200万人記念で作らせてもらいました！
but I got to make it for my 2 million subscribers milestone!
いいアイデアだよね、これね！
Isn't it a great idea?
探して、ちょっと見ていただくんですけど、
And take a look at this...
こちら、じゃじゃーん！
Tada! Here it is!
ヘアバンド！
A headband!
これ、みこぴーのヘアバンドになってます。
This is a Mikopee headband.
ちょっとふわふわしてる可愛いし、
It's all fluffy and cute,
ま、このピンもいっぱいついてて、
and it comes with lots of hairpins,
イヤリングも可愛くって！
plus these super cute earrings!
あと、このサクランボになってるんですよ、ネックレス！可愛い！
Also, this necklace has cherries on it! So cute!
で、このね、ダボっとした
And this oversized,
ニットね！
knit cardigan!
ま、ちょっとセクシーなね、ちょっとセクシーな…
A bit sexy, you know... slightly sexy...
ルームウェア、何て言いますかね、
roomwear, how should I put it...
あの、ちょっと、なかなかね、
Well, you know, normally,
みこちゃんはおへそを見せないんですけど、
Miko doesn't really show her belly button, but...
ちょっとおへそがね、見えます！
my belly button... is visible!
ちょっとあの、若干…
A little bit, well...
ね、寒くなるとね、食べたくなって、若干ぷにってる気もしなくもないけど…
When it gets cold, you eat more, so it feels a tiny bit squishy, maybe...
まあまあまあまあ！気にした者勝ちですからね！
Well, well, well! If you care, you lose!
大丈夫、健康的な範囲だからね！大丈夫、大丈夫！
It's fine, it's within a healthy range! It's okay, it's okay!
ということで！
So anyway!
あのね、隅々までちょっと見ていただきたいんですが…
I'd like you to check out every single detail, but...
もっとね、見ていただきたいところがあります！
there's something else I really want you to see!
見て！この…お部屋！可愛い！
Look! This... room! It's so cute!
本日のライブはなんと、トリバルコンさんにね、
For today's live stream, Tribalcon...
制作をあの、お願いさせていただきまして、作ってもらいました！
graciously made this stage set for us upon request!
本当にどうもありがとうございます！めっちゃ可愛いの！
Thank you so very much! It's incredibly cute!
もう本当にね、みこぴーとかね、
Really, the Mikopees and...
このソファとかね、めちゃくちゃ細かく作っていただいて言います！
this sofa and everything were made with such incredible detail!
この後もね、ちょっとね、びっくりするギミックとかもありますのでお楽しみに！
There are also some surprising features coming up later, so look forward to it!
じゃあね！
Now then!
あ、そうだ！ハッシュタグだ！ハッシュタグ！
Oh, right! The hashtag! The hashtag!
ハッシュタグは、えー、こちら！
The hashtag is, um, this one!
さくらみこ新衣装クリスマスライブでね、応援してください！
Please tweet using "#さくらみこ新衣装XmasLIVE" to support us!
スクショもたくさん撮ってね！
Take lots of screenshots, too!
ちょっとスクショタイム！
Screenshot time!
はい！キダダン！
Okay! Ta-da!
あ、可愛い！あ、可愛い！あ、可愛い！可愛い！可愛い！あ、可愛い！はい、可愛い！はい、可愛い！
Ah, cute! Ah, cute! Ah, cute! Cute! Cute! Ah, cute! Yes, cute! Yes, cute!
はい、可愛い！はい、可愛い！はい、可愛い！
Yes, cute! Yes, cute! Yes, cute!
ということでね、みんなたくさん撮ったよね？
So, everyone got plenty of screenshots, right?
はい、お願いします！
Yes, please share them!
そして！なんと最後に重大告知も！
And! There's also a major announcement at the end!
ありますので、最後までぜひお見逃しなく！
Make sure not to miss a single moment until the very end!
ありがとう！よろしくね！
Thank you! Hope you enjoy it!
それでは、次の曲行きますか！
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
こちらにね、お移動させていただきまして…
Moving over to this spot...
はい！
Alright!
それでは、次の曲、いっくぞー！
Now then, next song... let's go!
半端ないっぱっぱっぱっぱっぱっぱ（へい）
Unbelievable pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa (Hey)
限界突破っぱっぱっぱっぱっぱ（へい）
Breaking limits pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa (Hey)
毎日半端ないっぱっぱっぱっぱっぱ（へい）
Every day is unbelievable pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa (Hey)
限界突破っぱっぱっぱっぱっぱ（へい）
Breaking limits pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa (Hey)
最適温度 uh 遮るゴースト
Optimal temperature uh obstructing ghosts
八百万の 嫌な外的要素
Countless unpleasant external factors
「何の気ない」と 超あっけらかんと
Saying "It's nothing," so nonchalantly
悪気もなく邪魔するどっかの誰かさんにバイバイ
Saying bye-bye to someone who rudely intrudes without ill intent
自分時間 堕落タイム確保 17時〜9時は死守マスト
Securing me-time and slacking-off time, 5 PM to 9 AM is a must-protect
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに
Plus not forgetting love, romance, and sweets
ととのつまり オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
In short, overworking is strictly off-limits, I'm warning you
ねぇ楽しくて苦しくなくて生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living a fun, pain-free life is pretty tough, huh?
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」甘い蜜には罠がある
Because "stability," "shortcuts," and "cramming"—sweet honey always has a trap
やっ！
Ya!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleeping when I get sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Waking up after noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
Playing because I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eating when I'm hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laughing when I'm happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
Crying when I'm sad is totally fine, right?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
Doing my best today somehow for the sake of tomorrow's me
明日もう頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
Working hard today so I don't have to work hard tomorrow
怠惰じゃないや これ多分そうだ
It's not laziness, or maybe it is
なんやでやることやっています！
One way or another, I'm getting things done!
WHAT? & BUT
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
It doesn't matter if nobody knows about it
私には私のマイルール
I have my own rules
明日ラクするためにはハイチーズ
Say "cheese" to make tomorrow easier
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある毎日を生きてきたいのです
Surprisingly, I just want to live every day filled with love and peace like this
Don't be Don't be Don't be shy
ドキドキしていたい
I want my heart to throb with excitement
Let Let Let me shine
明日天気になれ
May tomorrow bring sunny weather
To To To be excite
心もっと踊りたい
I want my heart to dance even more
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday
木金土日月
Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday, Monday
辛くなったら歌う
Singing when things get tough
むかついたら愚痴る
Complaining when I get annoyed
やりたいようにやる
Doing whatever I want to do
それができたら苦労しないわ
If it were that easy, nobody would suffer!
常に一喜一憂
Constantly swaying between joy and grief
適度にセーフレスクは回避しつつつでまあ頑張るのさ
Properly avoiding safe risks, well, I'll do my best!
適当に今日までは言うまいがまあ頑張るのさ
I won't say I've been slacking until today, but well, I'll do my best!
夢の中では...
In my dreams...
ずっとべーたらしてやるんだ
I'm gonna laze around forever!
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく明日の私のため (Fight)
Not for someone else, but for tomorrow's me! (Fight)
楽するために苦しいことも乗り越えちゃうんだからね (Fight)
I'll even overcome tough times just to make things easy later! (Fight)
やりたくないことやらないためにやりたくないことやれ (Fight)
Do what you don't wanna do, so you won't have to do what you don't wanna do! (Fight)
あれ？これって結果頑張れてる？私とっても偉いじゃないか！ (Fight)
Huh? Does this mean I'm actually trying hard? Aren't I super praiseworthy?! (Fight)
自分時間 堕落タイム確保 17時〜9時は死守マスト
Securing "me time" & lazy time; 5 PM to 9 AM is a must-protect!
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに ととのつまり
Plus, without forgetting love, romance, or sweets! In short...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
Warning: Overwork is strictly prohibited! I'm giving notice!
ねぇ楽しくて苦しくなくて生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living a life that's fun and pain-free is pretty hard, huh?
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」甘い蜜には罠がある
Because in "stability," "cheats," and "cramming," sweet honey always has a trap!
やっ！
Ya!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleep when you get sleepy,
お昼過ぎに起きる
wake up after noon,
遊びたくて遊ぶ
play when you wanna play,
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
eat when you get hungry,
嬉しかったら笑う
laugh when you're happy,
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
and if you're sad, isn't it okay to cry?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of tomorrow's me, I'll somehow do my best today!
明日もう頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll work hard today so I don't have to work hard tomorrow!
半端ないっぱっぱーらっぱっぱーらっぱー (へい)
Unbelievable, pa-ppa-ra-ppa-ppa-ra-ppa! (Hey!)
限界突破っぱーらっぱっぱーらっぱー (へい)
Breaking through limits, pa-ppa-ra-ppa-ppa-ra-ppa! (Hey!)
毎日半端ないっぱっぱーらっぱっぱーらっぱー (へい)
Every day unbelievable, pa-ppa-ra-ppa-ppa-ra-ppa! (Hey!)
限界突破っぱーらっぱっぱーらっぱー
Breaking through limits, pa-ppa-ra-ppa-ppa-ra-ppa!
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“XX”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know... I know you're all alone doing "XX".
ピクンピクン震えてさ 声もダダ漏れなんだわ
Trembling and twitching, and your voice is leaking out!
正直に言っちゃえよ バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ 効いてんの？
Just be honest! It's obvious anyway, so speak up! Is it working?
普通普通 恥ずかしい？ みんな隠しているだけ むふっ
It's totally normal! Embarrassed? Everyone's just hiding it... Ehe.
モニタリング
[Title: Monitoring]
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“涙”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know... I know you're crying all by yourself.
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and feeling down, singing weak-hearted karaoke alone in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース もっと泣いたって 何度だって受け止めてあげる
We're on the "Together Until Morning" course! Even if you cry more, I'll accept you anytime!
もう我慢しないでいっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out, okay?
MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you!
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake with my talent for love!
泣いてくれなきゃ 溺れてしまう 濡れていたい
If you don't cry for me, I'll drown... I wanna stay soaked!
ねぇいいでしょう？ 舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I wanna lick it off and drink it all up!
MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you!
頼り散らして シックラブ なんて最高ね
Depending on me completely, sick love—isn't that the best?
分けてくれなきゃ きみの“痛い”感じていたい
Share it with me! I wanna feel your "pain"!
ねぇいいでしょう？ 吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I wanna suck it out and save you!
見たい...
I wanna see...
見たいの きみの中
I wanna see inside of you...
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり悔しがってんの知ってるよ
Hey, I know... I know you're feeling frustrated all alone.
ズキュンズキュン高まるじゃん きみを推すことをやめない
My heart goes thump-thump! I'll never stop supporting you!
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみはできる子 知ってるよ
Hey, I know... I know you're capable!
つらい時は 弱いくらいで丁度いい あたしそれでも好きだよ
When it's tough, being weak is just fine! I love you either way!
MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you!
名前を呼んでよ いつだって 会いに参上
Call my name! I'll come see you anytime!
きみはひとりだ だから歌う「ひとりじゃない」
You are only one person, that's why I sing "You are not alone"!
もういいでしょう ソロプレイはお終いなんだってば
Isn't it enough already? Playing solo is over!
きみが病めるときも あたし側にいるわ
Even when you're sick, I'll be right by your side.
いつも見守っているわ そうよ怖くないのよ
I'm always watching over you, that's right, don't be afraid.
MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you!
慰めさせて シェイクシェイク 愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake with my talent for love!
泣いてくれなきゃ 溺れてしまう 濡れていたい
If you don't cry for me, I'll drown... I wanna stay soaked!
ねぇいいでしょう？ 舐め取って 飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I wanna lick it off and drink it all up!
MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you!
頼り散らして シックラブ なんて最高ね
Depending on me completely, sick love—isn't that the best?
分けてくれなきゃ きみの“痛い”感じていたい 覗いていたい
Share it with me! I wanna feel your "pain", I wanna peek inside!
吸い取って 救いたいんだってば
I wanna suck it out and save you!
ねぇあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“涙”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know... I know you're crying all by yourself.
グスングスン凹んでさ 弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sniffling and feeling down, singing weak-hearted karaoke alone in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース もっと泣いたって
We're on the "Together Until Morning" course! Even if you cry more...
何度だって受け止めてあげる もう我慢しないで出してってってば さあ
I'll accept you anytime! Don't hold back anymore, let it out! Come on!
ずーっといっしょ！
[Title: Together Forever!]
充電器を貸して！
Lend me your charger!
またあなたのせいであたしすり減った
I got worn down because of you again.
終電見逃して
Missed the last train,
またあたしのせいで帰れなくなった
and couldn't go home because of me again.
繋がっていようね、消耗戦に持ち込んで
Let's stay connected, dragging into a war of attrition.
お互いに足を引っ張ったアオハル
Our youth where we held each other back,
沈殿した思い出でずっといっしょ！
with settled memories, together forever!
参観日にだって
Even on parents' day,
誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
I felt like nobody was looking at me.
散々シニカルって
Being so cynical,
昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
I tried not to expect anything from the city in daylight.
そうやって守った孤独さえめちゃくちゃになった
Even the loneliness I protected like that was ruined.
あたしだって死にたくて仕方ない
I want to die so badly too.
こんな顔だいじにしたいと思えないもん
I can't care about a face like this.
共に過ごした日々が
The days we spent together,
ささやかな幸せが
the modest happiness,
かけがえのないトラウマになってくれたらいいな
I hope it becomes an irreplaceable trauma.
はなればなれなんて誰かが吐かせたバグだよね？
Being separated is just a bug someone spewed out, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is something precious?
A. 今失くしたそれ
A. The thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back.
健やかなるときも病めるときも
In sickness and in health,
グロい履歴の中で
within this grotesque history,
ずっといっしょ！
together forever!
もうちょっとふつうに
A little more normally,
悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to feel sad about sad things.
長調のチューンに
To a major key tune,
感情委託して楽になりたかった
I wanted to entrust my feelings and feel at ease.
「せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね」
"Please do your best to live life to the fullest."
あたしだって死にたくて仕方ない
I want to die so badly too.
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be at the mercy of a song like that.
あなただけひとりで
All by yourself,
あたしの目を盗んで
behind my back,
幸せになろうなんて思わないで
don't even think about becoming happy.
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から
Ever since the night you dried my hair,
あたしは壊されたんだよ
I was broken.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your lifelong regret,
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
like a ring that won't come off.
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている、最低だよ
Flashing back over and over again, it's the worst.
一緒に居た時の方があたし可愛かったなあ
I was cuter back when we were together.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is something precious?
A. 今失くしたそれ
A. The thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back.
健やかなるときも病めるときも
In sickness and in health,
他の誰かと眠っていても
even if you're sleeping with someone else,
お揃いの悪夢でずっといっしょ！
together forever in a matching nightmare!
天天天天天天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天天天国地獄国！
Heaven, heaven, heaven, Hell country!
Open Sesame
闇と光の交わる fanatic
A fanatic intersection of dark and light
今宵味わう psychedelic
Tasting psychedelic vibes tonight
踊り絡まりあう zodiac
Dancing and intertwining zodiac
恋の駆け引きの tie-break
The tie-break in love's tactics
飾らない 存在 ただ気を惹きたい
Unadorned existence, I just want to attract attention
夢心地 触れ合い 惑わせたい
Dreamlike touch, I want to mesmerize
曖昧 溶けない cocktailは甘い
Vague and undissolved cocktail is sweet
鮮やかな赤いeye 見つめて限界
Staring into vivid red eyes at the limit
月夜に誘われ 天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔が
Enticed by the moonlit night, angels and demons, angels and demons, angels and demons
偶(たま)さか接した 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Chance encounters of heaven and hell, heaven and hell, heaven and hell
狭間で出会った 天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔が
Met in the threshold, angels and demons, angels and demons, angels and demons
集まって踊れば 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 門が開く
When gathered to dance, the gates of heaven and hell, heaven and hell open
闇と光の交わる fanatic
A fanatic intersection of dark and light
今宵味わう psychedelic
Tasting psychedelic vibes tonight
踊り絡まりあう zodiac
Dancing and intertwining zodiac
恋の駆け引きの tie-break
The tie-break in love's tactics
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death
Birth Birth
Death Birth Death
Let's go!
生きた魂を trayに置いて
Placing a living soul on a tray,
めくる5枚の card 揺れる炎
turning five cards, flickering flames.
先にあなたが raiseしたなら
If you raise first,
もう迷わない glass飲み干して
hesitate no more, drink up the glass.
今夜 All-in 降りない この勝負
Tonight all-in, won't fold in this showdown.
いま、天国と地獄をつなぐ門が開いてゆく。
Now, the gate connecting heaven and hell opens.
天使と悪魔、死者と生者が入り乱れ、踊り、笑い、
Angels and demons, the dead and the living mingle, dancing and laughing,
すべては混沌の中に飲み込まれてゆく。
Everything is swallowed into chaos.
それは世界の終焉であり、
It is the end of the world,
新たる始まりでもあるのだった。
and also a new beginning.
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death
Birth Birth
Death Birth Death
天天天天天国
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天天天天天国地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
天天天天天国
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天天天天天国地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
天天天天天国
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天天天天天国地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
月夜に誘われ 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Invited by the moonlit night, angels and demons...
偶さか接した 天国 地獄の
happened to meet between heaven and hell,
恍惚消えない 果てない moon-night
an unforgettable, endless moonlit night.
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Of heaven and hell, of heaven and hell,
狭間で出会った 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
meeting in between, angels and demons,
集まって踊れば 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
gathering to dance in heaven and hell!
狭間で出会った 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Meeting in between, angels and demons,
集まって踊れば dance dance dance dance
gathering to dance, dance, dance, dance!
天天天天天国
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天天天天天国地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
天天天天天国
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven
天天天天天国地獄
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, hell
回想中熱くなりお茶いかが？冷静に大人で
Getting worked up reminiscing, how about tea?
ハートは君にまだ教えずにご相談チラチラと
Before revealing my heart, glancing for advice.
余裕 身に着けて言う「お相手はYou?」 ドラマのようなことしない女優
Acting composed, asking "Is your partner you?"
噛めば噛むほど美味しいLady例に甘え方を見せてほしい
A lady sweeter over time, show me how to be spoiled.
はみ出したい ん～変われないの 自由型のいい子は好き放題
Wanting to break free, but unable to change...
その塩梅 も～わからないの 優しいふりしてただ焦ってる
I don't know the balance, panicking inside.
要求はさりげなくお茶濁し嬉しさをごまかし
Casual requests to dodge the point, hiding joy.
反省会駆け引きを学びたい 裏技をつらつらと
A reflection meeting to learn tactics and tricks.
至急きっかけのキュー！慌ててもCute そんな事なんて仕立てないIQ
Urgent cue! Cute even when flustered...
あの手この手も出来ないLady例におとしまとめてほしい
A lady without trickery, please wrap things up.
遠慮して ん～はじけないの まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
Holding back, unable to let loose...
そのボーダー も～超えらんないの そもそも話まだ隠してる
I can't cross that boundary, hiding the real story.
(読めない 読めない) 恋は (読めない 読めない)
(Unpredictable) Love is (unpredictable)
そっと口角上げ君を...魅せ君を...
Gently smiling at you... enchanting you...
(包み包み) そっと心タップ 君を...あぁ君を
(Enfolding) Gently tapping your heart, you... ah, you
(包み包み) 知りたい
(Enfolding) I want to know.
はみ出したい ん～変われないの 自由型のいい子は好き放題
Wanting to break free, but unable to change...
その塩梅 も～わからないの
I don't know the right balance anymore,
優しいふりしてただ焦ってもっと
pretending to be sweet while panicking even more,
ん～はじけないの
mm~ unable to let loose.
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead you smoothly, but...
そのボーダー も〜超えらんないの
I can't even cross that border...
そもそも話まだ隠して 見つめてる
I'm still keeping quiet about it and just staring.
Snow halation
[Song: Snow halation]
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, this feeling right now.
空から降ってきたみたい
It's like it came falling down from the sky.
特別な季節の色が ときめきを見せるよ
The colors of this special season bring excitement.
初めて出会った時から
From the moment we first met,
予感に騒ぐ心のMelody
my heart's melody stirs with premonitions.
とめられないとまらない な・ぜ
It can't be stopped, won't stop... why?
届けて切なさには
Reach out! To this heartrending pain,
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
shall we give it a name: "Snow halation"?
想いが重なるまで待てずに 悔しいけど好きって純情
I can't wait for our feelings to overlap; it's frustrating, but love is pure.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
Even with this mild fever, hesitation won't do.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
I agree with the courage to dive in—it's starting soon!!
音もなく気配もなく
Without a sound, without a trace,
静かに運命は変わる
fate changes in silence.
これからの未来に胸の 鼓動が早くなる
Thinking of the future ahead, my heart's pulse quickens.
例えば困った時には
For instance, whenever you're in trouble,
すぐ駆けつけて抱きしめたくて
I want to rush over right away and hold you tight,
どこにいてもどこでも Fly high
wherever you are, anywhere—fly high!
急いでいつの間にか
Hurry up! Before I knew it,
大きくなりすぎた “True emotion”
it grew far too large, this "True emotion".
夢だけみてる様じゃつらいよ 恋人は君って言いたい
Just dreaming about it is painful; I want to tell you that my lover is you.
優しい目が とまどってるイヤだよ
I don't like seeing your gentle eyes bewildered.
このまま一気に愛情 あずけてPlease!!
Entrust all your love to me at once, please!!
届けて切なさには
Reach out! To this heartrending pain,
名前をつけようか “Snow halation”
shall we give it a name: "Snow halation"?
想いが重なるまで待てずに 悔しいけど好きって純情
I can't wait for our feelings to overlap; it's frustrating, but love is pure.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
Even with this mild fever, hesitation won't do.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
I agree with the courage to dive in—it's starting soon!!
はい！みんな楽しんでくれてますかー？
Alright! Is everyone enjoying themselves?
ゲストもね、たくさん来てくださいました！みんなありがとー！
We had so many guests come today too! Thank you, everyone!
探して、見てください！
And look at this!
ステージもちょっとね、ぐるーっと回転して、外にやってきました！凄くないですか？
The stage rotated around a bit, and now we're outside! Isn't this amazing?
ちょっとイルミネーションもね、綺麗でね。もうクリスマスって感じで。ちょっと... まぁちょっと若干肌寒いですが、ねー？
The illuminations are so pretty too, it really feels like Christmas. It's... well, a bit chilly, but right?
もう、すっごい綺麗だよね！見てー！すごい！
It's seriously so pretty! Look! Wow!
はい！どうもありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you so much!
そして、なんと次で最後の曲になるんですが...
And now, unbelievable as it is, the next song will be the last one...
なんと次の曲は、新曲です！
Incredibly, the next song is a brand new song!
みこちゃん、1stアルバム以来のね、ソロの新曲となりますー！
This will be Miko's first new solo song since her 1st album!
ソロライブを経て、みこがまた新たな一歩を踏み出す曲となっております。
After the solo live, this song represents Miko taking a brand new step forward.
それでは、聴いてください。咲き誇れ アイドル！
So then, please listen to... "Bloom Proudly, Idol"!
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on taking on challenges,
君と夢見るんだ
and dream together with you.
不器用で悪いか
So what if I'm clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I'm gonna bloom in full glory!
初のイベント 需要無しデフォ
My very first event defaultly had zero demand,
そんな私に夢を見ました
yet someone like me had a dream:
アイドルという生き方
A way of life called being an idol.
憧れて
Full of longing,
「無敵エリート」「笑顔はチート」
"Invincible elite", "A smile that cheats"...
こんな私を見てくれる君
To you, who look at someone like me,
好きなとこはどこですか？
what part of me do you like?
わがままを許して
Please forgive my selfishness.
ステージ経験値 涙滲んで
Stage experience points blurred by tears,
それでも絶対負けたくない
even so, I definitely don't want to lose!
桜にメッセージ乗せて届け
Carry my message upon the cherry blossoms and reach them,
愛で溢れますように
may it overflow with love.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on taking on challenges,
君と夢見るんだ
and dream together with you.
不器用で悪いか
So what if I'm clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a fantasy!
私らしく 桜色 ね♡
In my own way, cherry blossom pink, okay?♡
磨いたスキル 実力発揮
Polished skills, demonstrating my true ability,
楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
the days I can enjoy have been increasing.
アイドルとして生きてる
Living my life as an idol...
君のおかげ
It's all thanks to you!
アホ毛はキュート！ 勝ち確ルート！
An ahoge is cute! A guaranteed winning path!
そんな私についてきてよね！
So keep up with me, okay!
ドジなとこも許されて
Even my clumsy side is forgiven,
最強じゃん！
aren't I the strongest?!
痛いの言いたいの グッと飲み込んで
Swallowing down the pain and everything I want to complain about,
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to spread smiles with my own smile.
桜前線が君の町に
May the cherry blossom front reach your town,
春を届けるように
and bring the spring to you.
アイドルだけは
The one thing...
譲りたくないんだ
...I don't want to give up is being an idol!
君に見せたいんだ
I want to show you,
理想へ挑むよ
as I take on the challenge toward my ideal.
駆け抜けろ
Dash through!
最高景色見せてあげる
I'll show you the absolute best scenery!
信じていいよ 桜を
You can believe in it, in the cherry blossoms.
さあ皆で咲かそう
Come on, let's bloom together!
満開のピンクで世界染めて
Dye the world in full-bloom pink!
あぁこの涙はね
Ah, these tears of mine...
悲しい方じゃないから 安心をして
...aren't sad ones, so please don't worry.
きれいだね
It's beautiful, isn't it?
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on taking on challenges,
君と夢見るんだ
and dream together with you.
不器用で悪いか
So what if I'm clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a fantasy!
私らしく 桜色 ね♡
In my own way, cherry blossom pink, okay?♡
みんなー！
Everyone!
ピンクアイドルクリスマス 新衣装お披露目ライブを見てくれてどうもありがとー！
Thank you so much for watching the Pink Idol Christmas new outfit reveal live!
ここで告知が3つあります！
I have three announcements to make here!
まずはこちら！
First is this one!
200万人記念 ルームウェア衣装お披露目記念グッズが発売されます！
Commemorating 2 million subscribers, roomwear outfit reveal goods will be released!
キービジュアルは おるだん先生に描いてもらいました！いつもありがとうございます！
The key visual was drawn by Orudan-sensei! Thank you as always!
イラストのテーマはお部屋でのんびりしているみこねぇです！
The theme of the illustration is Miko relaxing in her room!
それでは 1つずつ見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's look at them one by one!
まずはこちら！
First is this!
リバーシブルブランケット！
Reversible Blanket!
表には35P 裏にはみこの大きなイラストが描いてあります！
The front features 35P, and the back has a large illustration of Miko!
丸めて包まれると みんなが35Pぬいぐるみになっちゃうよ！
If you roll up and wrap yourself in it, you'll become a 35P plushie!
続いて みちとおそろい35Pヘアバンド！
Next, Miko's matching 35P headband!
みこの新衣装とおそろいのヘアバンドです！
It's a headband matching Miko's new outfit!
毎日使いができるアイテムでしょう！使ってね！
It's a great item for everyday use! Please use it!
次は みちの愛用35Pマグカップです！
Next is Miko's favorite 35P mug!
お耳もついてるマグカップなんだよ！
It's a mug that even has ears on it!
ついに再現できました！
We were finally able to recreate it!
飲み物を入れても良し 小物入れにするも良し！
Great for drinks or as an accessory holder!
素敵なお家タイムのお供に使ってね！
Please use it to accompany your wonderful time at home!
最後は ルームウェアみちの35Pぎゅっ♡おねんねぬいぐるみです！
Lastly, Roomwear Miko's 35P Hugging Sleepy Plushie!
ルームウェア衣装のミコがぬいぐるみになりました！
Miko in her roomwear outfit has become a plushie!
みんなも一緒におやすみしようね！
Let's all go to sleep together!
フルセットはこんな感じです！
The full set looks like this!
そしてそして！フルセット特典はポストカードです！
And also! The full set bonus is a postcard!
今回は箔押しの複製サインとメッセージ付きとなっております！
This time it comes with a foil-stamped signature and message!
みんな ぜひぜひ購入してくださいね！
Everyone, please be sure to purchase it!
告知2つ目はこちら！
The second announcement is this!
本日初披露した新曲「咲き誇れアイドル」が本日0時から配信開始！
The new song "Sakihokore Idol" revealed today will be available for streaming from midnight tonight!
ファーストソロライブを終えて 次のステージに向かっていく気持ちをHoneyWorksさんに書き下ろしていただきました！
HoneyWorks wrote this song for me, expressing my feelings heading toward the next stage after my first solo live!
そしてそして！この後「咲き誇れアイドル」のMVがプレミア公開となります！
And also! Right after this, the MV for "Sakihokore Idol" will premiere!
とっても可愛いので みんなたくさん聴いて見てくださいね！
It's super cute, so please listen to it and watch it a lot!
告知3つ目はこちら！
The third announcement is this!
なんと！さくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗のコラボが2026年も決定しました！
Surprisingly, a collaboration between Sakura Miko and Naruto Taiyaki Honpo is set for 2026 too!
なんと4回目ですよ！
It's actually our 4th time!
今回の開催期間は2026年2月20日から3月31日までです！
The event period this time is from February 20 to March 31, 2026!
やったー！
Yay!
本当にね こんなに長く続いているのはみんなのおかげでもありますし 鳴門鯛焼本舗さん 本当にありがとうございます！
Really, that it has continued for so long is thanks to everyone, and Naruto Taiyaki Honpo, thank you so much!
詳細情報は後日またXのほうで告知するので 楽しみにしていてくださいね！
Detailed info will be announced later on X, so please look forward to it!
今日は本当にありがとう！みんな！
Thank you so much for today, everyone!
メリークリスマス！
Merry Christmas!
おつみこでした！
Thanks for coming! Otsumiko!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!